

Kim Valkama

E-mail: kim.valkama@protonmail.com Website: valkama.kim

Phone: +358 445959906 Address: Ullantorpantie 7 b 17,

02750, Espoo

Interests

Senior System administrator, junior developer and future DevOps expert. Anything "impossible to develop" is just a challenge. Will strive for automating my task so that I can focus on automating my next task. Prefers remote work unless I'm responsible for keeping the local network working. Started off my career maintaining Mac and windows, nowadays prefer working with Linux. Opensource enthusiast, want to learn Assembly programming one day.

Work experience

Pharazon AB

May 2020 — Still active

System Administrator

Development, deployment and maintenance of company servers

Device and service acquisition and integration

Responsible for System Administration and environment configuration

Data Systems

December 2019 — March 2020

Webstore maintainer/administrator

Working in one of the biggest IT webstores in Finland, as the company is run by 2 people most of the work responsibilities are also shared by both workers.

During my time at Data Systems i have had full resposibility of all techincal issues we face, including; Data backups, device troubleshooting and maintenance, network device installations and hardware upgrades.

Most work weeks include, purchase processing, updating product information for our webpage, product categorizing, making sales offers to B2B customers, investigating faulted orders. DOA and RMA returns for faulty products. Product investigation for customers. Custom IT jobs for customers and special order investigations.

Running the redistribution of products and pickup shipments have been mostly my responsibility, as the other worker has been working remotely 3/4 of the time i have been here.

CycleIT

February 2019 — October 2020

Entrepreneur

Started working as a freelancer doing IT support, data backup, design jobs and development.

February 2019 started working as a freelancer.

Spring of 2019 worked for several companies outside of IT field, while also running CycleIT on the side. December 2019 started registration process for CycleIT, slowed down the growth of my enterpreneurship for a job opportunity that requires most of my focus.

Kim Valkama

January 2020 CycleIT became a official company.

Current customers are mostly small bussinesses, most customer jobs are IT support related. Occasionally customers request banner designs, website updates or help with webhost functionality.

Current website can be found at www.cycleit.fi

Note that current website is still built with pure html/css/javascript, hopefully in the near future i will be ablet to switch over to wordpress.

Bauhaus

August 2019 — Decemember 2019

Salesman

Worked as a salesman 30/h a week for bauhaus as a tools and small machines salesman.

Did occasional IT troubleshooting while working here.

Heavily focused on evening and weekend shifts.

Had to end my contract at Bauhaus for an exceptional job offering.

Retail Logistics Excellence - RELEX

May 2017 — February 2019

Application Specialist

Maintenance, installation, upgrading and troubleshooting of in-house built application for customers.

Normal issues would include file issues, crashed or unstable processes, server memory issues and ERP database integration issues, and more. Worked with Linux infrastructure only (excluding customer infrastructure).

Worked with some outside of the scope issues as well, some network support, server maintenance, Linux desktop support.

Integral Oy

June 2013 — January 2017

System Administrator

Workstation and Server maintenance and installation.

- Windows Workstations (All releases including Windows PE)
- Windows Servers (AD, SQL, DHCP, IIS, exchange, releases NT 5.0 and newer)
- Limited Linux server maintenance (Firewall, backup server)

Experience in troubleshooting and repairing a lot of different devices in a network, Printers, routers, mac workstations, android/mac/windows phones, occasionally customer specific devices (e.g card readers, tape printers and video cameras)

Computer security, firewall maintenance, workstation security and restoration.

Resolving and fulfilling customer IT requests.

Worked a long time as customer first contact.

Siscotec

June 2010 — June 2012

Construction Worker

Summer Job for several summers.

Taking down old apartments, construction work, repairing public structures. Worked on simple construction projects and worked as a helping hand on bigger projects.

Kim Valkama 2

Education

Bachelor of business administration (BBA)

August 2013 — December 2016

Laurea University of Applied Sciences

Information Technology and Business administration.

Due to personal interest focused more on computer networking, development and security than the business and administration side of the studies.

References

References available upon request.

Kim Valkama